<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kubernetes Stack for Academia on hypathia.net</title>
    <link>/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kubernetes Stack for Academia on hypathia.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Everything is mine</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 06:30:49 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>/en/day_0/introduction.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 06:30:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_0/introduction.html</guid>
      <description>Mission hypathia.net aims to provide a blueprint for operating a service to provide cloud based computing resources in a self-service manner. It presents an opinionated selection of components, configurations and practices tailored to environments that have a specific set of requirements, often found at academic institutions.
Assumed Requirements These are the main requirements that shaped the specific characteristics of hypathia.net:
 The organisation cannot use computing resources of a public cloud provider This may be due to procurement rules, legal obligations or the wish to run highly sensitive workloads in-house, rather than on hardware that the organization has virtually no control over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prerequisites</title>
      <link>/en/day_0/prerequisites.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 16:29:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_0/prerequisites.html</guid>
      <description>Infrastructure Environment You will need
 a network with Internet access as well as a sufficient number of available IP addresses. Be sure to allow for growth (even when successful beyond your wildest dreams!). Migrating the cluster from one network to another is possible, but not for the faint of heart. a DNS domain and a mechanism to integrate it with your super-domain (eg. compute-cloud.example.com). entries for all your users in an Directory System that allows access via LDAP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>/en/day_1/networking.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 06:12:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_1/networking.html</guid>
      <description> Node Network Pod Network Automatic Certificate Generation Frontend / Load Balancer Make Service available to the World  add DNS resolution for name of the service. It should resolve to the IP Address of the frontend node. add line to /etc/haproxy/sni-domains.lst on the frontend node.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Configuration</title>
      <link>/en/day_1/global_config.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_1/global_config.html</guid>
      <description>When preparing the setup of a hypathia.net cluster, you will need to collect a few pieces information. You should prepare a shell script with these variables as defined below, so you can set them before generating configuration files. The names of the config details will be used in all further configuration templates shown on this website.
You must source the configuration file prior to the execution of any of the shell commands during the installation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Deployment Mojo</title>
      <link>/en/blog/secure-deployment-to-k8s.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 11:45:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/blog/secure-deployment-to-k8s.html</guid>
      <description>Deploying into the ICC Let&amp;rsquo;s assume the build pipeline of GitLab has finally succeeded and created a new container image. Naturally, now I want to have the pipeline deploy it into the cluster. Or to be more precise, to change the configuration of the cluster in such a manner, that it will pull the new image and then restart the ports according to the update rules of Deployments and Replica Sets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certificate Authority</title>
      <link>/en/day_1/certificate-authority.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_1/certificate-authority.html</guid>
      <description>Setting up a Certificate Authority and Creating TLS Certificates In this lab you will setup the necessary PKI infrastructure to secure the Kubernetes components. This lab will leverage CloudFlare&amp;rsquo;s PKI toolkit, cfssl, to bootstrap a Certificate Authority and generate TLS certificates to secure the following Kubernetes components:
 etcd kube-apiserver kubelet kube-proxy  After completing this lab you should have the following TLS keys and certificates:
admin.pem admin-key.pem ca-key.pem ca.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OS Update</title>
      <link>/en/day_3/os_update.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_3/os_update.html</guid>
      <description> Update CoreOS nodes With the help of the CoreOs auto-updater. By setting an annotation on those machines that need to be updated:
kubectl get nodes --context admin@hypathia | grep &amp;quot;coreos&amp;quot; | awk &#39; // { print $1 }&#39; | xargs -I NODE sh -c &#39;(kubectl annotate --context admin@hypathia --overwrite node NODE container-linux-update.v1.coreos.com/reboot-needed=&#39;true&#39;)&amp;amp;&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Protocol Address Management (IPAM)</title>
      <link>/en/day_1/ipam.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 06:45:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_1/ipam.html</guid>
      <description> foo
IP Adresses Installing the IAM Server (PowerDNS + d PXE Booting </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Management</title>
      <link>/en/day_1/image-management.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 11:15:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_1/image-management.html</guid>
      <description> Image Proxy Cache Private Registry Registry Permissions </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Permissions</title>
      <link>/en/day_0/permissions.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 06:30:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_0/permissions.html</guid>
      <description>User Groups User organize themself by creating projects and groups in Gitlab
Namespace Mapping Cluster Authentication LDAP Authentication kubelogin RBAC Service Accounts Capabilities The required capabilities for Conduit (a PSP with CAP_NET_ADM activated) are made availabe via a special service account conduit. Deployments that wish to use the Service Mesh must assign the service account in der deployment description.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupyter Hub</title>
      <link>/en/day_2/jupyter-hub.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 06:30:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_2/jupyter-hub.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Mesh (WIP)</title>
      <link>/en/day_2/service-mesh.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 15:30:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_2/service-mesh.html</guid>
      <description> Introduction A Service Mesh allows
Candidates are Linkerd, which is already build into some parts of Kubernetes, and Conduit, which is especially lightweight.
For both a multi-tenancy analysis and concept are missing as of yet.
Further Links Alternatives  Linkerd Conduit Istio  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>/en/day_0/references.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 06:30:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_0/references.html</guid>
      <description>Components of the hypathia.net Kubernetes (Kubernetes.io) A orchestration plattwork to help manage container based application.
Other Tools for Computational Science Joint Roadmap for Open Science Tools (JROST.org) A community working on a joint roadmap for open science tools.
SlateCI A plattform for offering services within a university campus</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Needed</title>
      <link>/en/day_0/help_needed.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 11:15:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_0/help_needed.html</guid>
      <description>Currently the are a number of holes in the automation of the hypathia system. It should be possible to close them, with the construction of a number of operators and controllers for the kubernetes system. An overview can be seen in this graphic:  Kubernetes Tenant Ecosystem   OwnerListAdmissionController In order to use tools like Draft, users have to be able to list namespaces. But as granting this right would result in exposing the information about other users namespaces, this is not permitted in the current settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/en/day_0/security_intro.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_0/security_intro.html</guid>
      <description>Take safety over security if performance is severly impacted. Take security whenever it is affordable.
Mulit-Tenancy is hard.
References Hard Multi-Tenancy in Kubernetes, Jessie Frazelle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/en/knowledge_base/multiple-identical-ingress.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/knowledge_base/multiple-identical-ingress.html</guid>
      <description>Symptoms All paths of an exported resources will show 503 Service Temporarily Unavailable for all paths.
Cause multiple ingress objects expose the same hostname
How to find it if site.example.com is the exposed name:
~$ kubectl get ingress --all-namespaces -o wide | grep site.example.com namespace1 name-ingress site.example.com 80, 443 4d mynamespace my-ingress site.example.com 80, 443 5d production prod-ingress site.example.com 80, 443 18h</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mouseion Inc.</title>
      <link>/en/company.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/company.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>