<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Day 0: Introduction on hypathia.net</title>
    <link>/en/day_0.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Day 0: Introduction on hypathia.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Everything is mine</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 06:30:49 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/en/day_0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Prerequisites</title>
      <link>/en/day_0/prerequisites.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 16:29:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_0/prerequisites.html</guid>
      <description>Infrastructure Environment You will need
 A etwork with Internet access as well as a sufficient number of available IP addresses. Be sure to allow for growth (even when successful beyond your wildest dreams!). Migrating the cluster from one network to another is possible, but not for the faint of heart. A DNS domain and a mechanism to integrate it with your super-domain (eg. compute-cloud.example.com). Entries for all your users in an Directory System that allows access via LDAP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vision</title>
      <link>/en/day_0/vision.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 11:40:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_0/vision.html</guid>
      <description>The long term vision of the documentation presented in this website is provide a template for Kubernetes installations that support users with highly variable skill sets and a excessive range of the workload size. Users may include people who have never written a program in their live as well as top-range researchers.
The system should provide the necessary aids and user interfaces to allow the writing of simple software without the need to install any local components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture</title>
      <link>/en/day_0/architecture.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 11:40:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_0/architecture.html</guid>
      <description>Architecture Overview  Hypathia.net Architecture   A Hypatha.net cluster is constructed from the following main components:
 Gitlab as main user interface for group management and version control, collaboration and communication. It also acts as the source of truth for user permissions and artifact ownership. While the Enterprise version offers useful additional functions, for operating a Hypathia-style cluster, the open-source version is sufficient.
 Kubernetes in a multi-tenant configuration for orchestrating containers based applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Permissions</title>
      <link>/en/day_0/permissions.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 06:30:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_0/permissions.html</guid>
      <description>User Groups User organize themself by creating projects and groups in Gitlab
Namespace Mapping Cluster Authentication LDAP Authentication kubelogin RBAC Service Accounts Capabilities The required capabilities for Conduit (a PSP with CAP_NET_ADM activated) are made availabe via a special service account conduit. Deployments that wish to use the Service Mesh must assign the service account in der deployment description.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>/en/day_0/references.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 06:30:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_0/references.html</guid>
      <description>Components of the hypathia.net Kubernetes (Kubernetes.io) A orchestration plattwork to help manage container based application.
Kubernetes Cluster Setup Projects  eznetes: Kubernetes the semi-hard way, a set of documents and shell scripts to semi automate the setup and maintenance of a on-prem cluster on bare-metal machines running CoreOS Container Linux.  Other Tools for Computational Science Joint Roadmap for Open Science Tools (JROST.org) A community working on a joint roadmap for open science tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Needed</title>
      <link>/en/day_0/help_needed.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 11:15:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_0/help_needed.html</guid>
      <description>Currently, the are a number of holes in the automation of the hypathia system. There are also parts that are unnecessarily complex. Most of these are the result of the organic growth of the system from it&amp;rsquo;s original incubation invironment.
Infrastructure Deploy Configuration Management System Hypathia.net has grown out of an environment that uses Puppet for configuration management. But this requires further infrastructure that is not worthwhile for setting up the few pet nodes that make up the Hypathia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/en/day_0/security_intro.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/day_0/security_intro.html</guid>
      <description>Take safety over security if performance is severly impacted. Take security whenever it is affordable.
Mulit-Tenancy is hard.
References Hard Multi-Tenancy in Kubernetes, Jessie Frazelle.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>